<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile on Codality</title>
    <link>https://blog.najmanowicz.com/categories/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile on Codality</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 21:03:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.najmanowicz.com/categories/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My private little G1/Android wish and hit list</title>
      <link>https://blog.najmanowicz.com/2009/03/30/my-private-little-g1android-wish-and-hit-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 21:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.najmanowicz.com/2009/03/30/my-private-little-g1android-wish-and-hit-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First of all, I have to say that I like the phone a lot. While you may get an impression from the rest of the post that I have a lot of beef with the phone, that&amp;rsquo;s really not the case. The very fact that I can compile a short, coherent list of things that I think could be improved upon, made me realize how little there is to be wishing for. And none of the problems is a deal breaker. It&amp;rsquo;s not like the phone is missing Copy&amp;amp;Paste or MMS ;). It does almost all I expected it to do (even in version 1.0), but since a few of my colleagues is looking forward to get one I thought I&amp;rsquo;d throw in a list of the little annoyances that I have faced using it, so they might verify how important the drawbacks might be to them. I am not sure how many of those can be addressed with third party applications but, for sure not all of them can, and I would definitely love Google to step in and provide a system-fix for them at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merged contacts in gmail rendered uneditable - the fix</title>
      <link>https://blog.najmanowicz.com/2009/02/28/merged-contacts-in-gmail-rendered-uneditable-the-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2009 12:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.najmanowicz.com/2009/02/28/merged-contacts-in-gmail-rendered-uneditable-the-fix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long story short. Bought G1 lately so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to bring peace to my tormented contact list once and for all. Editing in Gmail is&amp;hellip; adequate. I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to import most of my contacts - naturally countless of those were duplicates as I integrated my mail contact list and my phone contact list. Where gmail contacts list editing excels is at allowing you to merge those.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly convenient:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it Yeti? Is it a magazine? I sense disturbance in The Force</title>
      <link>https://blog.najmanowicz.com/2008/03/11/is-it-yeti-is-it-a-magazine-i-sense-disturbance-in-the-force/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 19:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.najmanowicz.com/2008/03/11/is-it-yeti-is-it-a-magazine-i-sense-disturbance-in-the-force/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s been a great link to an article forwarded to me today to a Newsweek&amp;rsquo;s Apple PR division Technology columnist Steven Levy. Where he claimed that he has lost (although he is not sure (LOL) ) his MacBook Air. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Apple/?p=1395&#34;&gt;blogosphere&lt;/a&gt; is throwing their hands up in the Air ;), but really&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s so funny on so many levels that people are all about the story (ironically so am I with this post). The article is such a great example of the Apple hype machine at its best. Let me elaborate&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nokia N95 - Just because I&#39;m cheap!</title>
      <link>https://blog.najmanowicz.com/2007/10/30/nokia-n95-just-because-im-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2007 02:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.najmanowicz.com/2007/10/30/nokia-n95-just-because-im-cheap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, with a little help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://kill-9.pl&#34;&gt;TDI&lt;/a&gt; some time ago I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully switched all my outgoing calls to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.voipdiscount.com/&#34;&gt;Voipdiscount&lt;/a&gt;, while at the same time moving my incoming calls&amp;rsquo; number to mobile provider through a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sagem.com/index.php?id=1161&amp;amp;L=0&#34;&gt;Sagem&lt;/a&gt; base station, all of this nicely integrated in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linksys.com/servlet/Satellite?c=L_Product_C2&amp;amp;childpagename=US%2FLayout&amp;amp;cid=1146582257191&amp;amp;pagename=Linksys%2FCommon%2FVisitorWrapper&#34;&gt;Linksys SPA3102&lt;/a&gt; gateway in a way that a regular person grabbing a phone at my desk cannot realize that at the current moment it&amp;rsquo;s a hybrid not really having much in common with the POTS, they expect to be using. All of this effectively reducing the monthly phone spending to a negligible monthly fee, just in time when my eldest starts to spend hours on the phone - great!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
