<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Studio on Codality</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1314/categories/visual-studio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Studio on Codality</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1314/categories/visual-studio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do not turn Sitecore Media Request protection off and protect older Sitecore versions with ImageGuard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1314/2015/05/15/do-not-turn-sitecore-media-request-protection-off-and-protect-older-sitecore-versions-with-imageguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1314/2015/05/15/do-not-turn-sitecore-media-request-protection-off-and-protect-older-sitecore-versions-with-imageguard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1314/images/SitecorePatched.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1314/images/SitecorePatched_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;SitecorePatched&#34; title=&#34;SitecorePatched&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;237&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The post is related to the image resize vulnerability fix introduced in Sitecore 7.5. To read more about the Sitecore fix go to the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://sdn.sitecore.net/Products/Sitecore%20V5/Sitecore%20CMS%207/ReleaseNotes/ChangeLog.aspx&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Release notes page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and search for ?Media request protection?. While I was holding off for a number of months on the publication of the post as it puts the attack vector in plainer sight that I would like it to be (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seanholmesby.com/images-not-resizing-in-sitecore-7-5-sitecore-8-0/&#34;&gt;while the community&lt;/a&gt; figured out &lt;a href=&#34;http://sitecorepromenade.blogspot.se/2014/11/sitecore-75-image-resizing-changes.html&#34;&gt;how to work with Media Resizing in a neat way&lt;/a&gt;) - but recently I&amp;rsquo;ve seen voices raised considering &lt;a href=&#34;http://coresighted.net/2015/05/13/sitecore-media-request-protection-gone-wild/&#34;&gt;turning the Media Request protection off&lt;/a&gt; which I hope you will not be doing after reading this post. The post will also tell you how to enable such security on your older versions of Sitecore.&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;So here&amp;rsquo;s the story&amp;hellip;. At some point in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cognifide.com/&#34;&gt;Cognifide&lt;/a&gt; we have performed a research around Sitecore security and one of my colleagues (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MarasM&#34;&gt;Marek&lt;/a&gt;)  found out that you could easily kill any Sitecore instance by performing an image resize attack on it. While the CMS did some rudimentary checks and limited the values of height and width you could still perform an attack by harvesting the images from the site and perform multiple parallel &amp;amp; iterative size increase or just plain use the scale parameter to achieve any image size. A result of such attack would be a a denial of service due to 100% CPU &amp;amp; memory usage and would potentially allow for filling the server drive by creating the endless number of scaling calls.&#xA;Marek was even kind enough to provide a proof of concept code that confirmed the hypothesis by performing attack on a few of our internal servers. The program would load the home page; parse to find images linked from it and perform resizing of the images in a number threads.&#xA;[&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore PowerShell Console in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1314/2013/01/29/sitecore-powershell-console-in-visual-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 17:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1314/2013/01/29/sitecore-powershell-console-in-visual-studio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TheRocksGuy&#34;&gt;Jakob&lt;/a&gt; suggested that putting the Sitecore PowerShell Console in Visual Studio might not be a bad idea. He even provided me with the boilerplate code that served as a stub for the module (Thanks a million Jakob!).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So after some struggling on my part &lt;a href=&#34;http://marketplace.sitecore.net/en/Modules/Sitecore_PowerShell_Console_for_Sitecore_Rocks.aspx&#34;&gt;the new module is now on the Sitecore Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;. There is really not much to write about. If you like PowerShell and Sitecore Rocks you will find it pretty neat. Otherwise I&amp;rsquo;m afraid those are not the droids you are looking for&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerShell Console for Sitecore in your own code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1314/2012/04/06/using-powershell-console-for-sitecore-in-your-own-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 14:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1314/2012/04/06/using-powershell-console-for-sitecore-in-your-own-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All of the PowerShell blog posts so far were about using the console. Being the developer however, you probably think &amp;ndash; well that&amp;rsquo;s good for admins, but what&amp;rsquo;s in it for me? How can I benefit from it in my code? Well you can. With the latest update you can run the PowerShell environment in your application and take advantage of its scripting power, by getting the results out of it and pulling them into your app.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SoakIE – a Web Server Stress Tool with a twist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1314/2009/05/10/soakie-a-web-server-stress-tool-with-a-twist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 15:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1314/2009/05/10/soakie-a-web-server-stress-tool-with-a-twist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week or so ago a couple of friends in another project in Cognifide has run into a wall while trying to load test their website. the problem was as follows: The website is highly AJAX based – the page merely loads a stub in the initial request but then loads the rest of its data in a dynamic matter therefore a traditional web testing tools are fairly useless. What they tried was to setup a number of Selenium clients to pound the server, but that turned out to be fairly challenging to the machine doing the testing. It was not possible to set up more than 10 clients on a fairly strong machine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft loves programmers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1314/2007/03/09/microsoft-loves-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 19:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1314/2007/03/09/microsoft-loves-programmers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just read a &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2007/03/08/new-c-orcas-language-features-automatic-properties-object-initializers-and-collection-initializers.aspx&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; about a few new additions to &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/vcsharp/aa336745.aspx&#34;&gt;C# 3.0&lt;/a&gt; and in the context of what we&amp;rsquo;ve already learned about the whole &amp;ldquo;Orcas&amp;rdquo; project that is the simplest conclusion.&#xA;Microsoft .Net Framework designers and coders are just a bunch of programmers who you can clearly see enjoy hat they do. I can&amp;rsquo;t stress enough how many times I&amp;rsquo;ve been annoyed to be forced to wrap some private variables in the obvious public properties. No longer!&#xA;Instantiating a class followed by a bunch of setting of properties? Now done in one line. Shweet.&#xA;One may argue that C# is a set of such syntactic sugar. But then again, I am sure that&amp;rsquo;s why so many programmers really like it. Even some of the most Java oriented programmers (Yes Albert I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you!) in our company are looking forward to work on .Net.&#xA;It is the general perception here that, comparing to Eclipse, Visual Studio is a weak IDE in terms of pure code-writing-helpers, refactoring, and discovery of code dependencies. Only the next version will even be able to target more than 1 .net framework version&amp;hellip; Please fix that crap&amp;hellip; But the language designers are continually doing a great job.&#xA;Have a read on some:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EPiServer fun</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1314/2006/12/14/episerver-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2006 15:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1314/2006/12/14/episerver-fun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EPiServer is an Interesting technology we&amp;rsquo;ve started working on recently. I will try to blog my impressions and the progress over the course of learning the solution.&#xA;Since I just seem unable to learn by reading docs I chose to build an email obfuscating (antispam) control and a paged search as an exercise and a way to learn the guts of the EPiServer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-couple-of-loose-thoughts-for-a-start&#34;&gt;A couple of loose thoughts for a start&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;translation&#34;&gt;Translation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not sure I fully appreciate the way the translation is performed for the parts of the system that is editor independent . The translation is done by means of xml files stored on the disk in the /lang folder.&#xA;Basically what that means is that it&amp;rsquo;s much more prone to missing translations and thus is not as translation friendly as it could fairly easily be.&#xA;For the content I can always fall back to the e.g. english version and look what&amp;rsquo;s the original value there. not so much for the framework translations. Is there a tool for that? I will investigate that later as we&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to create a number of controls for the website we&amp;rsquo;ll be working on soon, and that will need to be translated to many languages. And not just that but also the original template files - we will need much more than what&amp;rsquo;s available originally in EPiServer.&#xA;So once you define your control&amp;rsquo;s content:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1314/2006/12/08/linkage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 12:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1314/2006/12/08/linkage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done some research about Visual studio plugins recently, just so that I can close the tabs and move on here are some links that I cound to contain some useful information:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jtleigh.com/people/colin/software/CopySourceAsHtml/&#34;&gt;HTML Code copy -Absolute must for any blogging .Net developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://watin.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;WatiN - Web applications testing in .Net - sounds like it might be THE framework for testing our web GUIs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/msdnmag/issues/05/12/VisualStudioAddins/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Add-Ins Every Developer Should Download Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devx.com/vstudioextensibility/Door/32727&#34;&gt;Microsoft Visual Studio Extensibility Contest Winners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dotnetslackers.com/articles/vs_addin/Introduction_ghostdoc.aspx&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roland-weigelt.de/ghostdoc/&#34;&gt;GhostDoc&lt;/a&gt; - really funny tool that needs to be looked at - might be useful&amp;hellip;. moderately. Definitely genuine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codekeep.net/&#34;&gt;CodeKeep - THE repository for storing and sharing code snippets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/PackInstaller&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Power toys pack installer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://devlicio.us/blogs/christopher_bennage/archive/2006/10/18/Your-Development-Tools.aspx&#34;&gt;Christopher Bennage lists some nice and worth mentioning tools as well&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/&#34;&gt;Seems like an interesting sanbox for some cool development ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.msdn.com/fxcop/&#34;&gt;FX Cop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kiwidude.com/blog/&#34;&gt;NCoverExplorer - test coverage tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ieaddons.com/AddOn.aspx?cid=2&amp;amp;scid=70&amp;amp;aid=a9bcc859-8419-4b67-aac3-e1b3e9749414&#34;&gt;This is not really a .Net stuff biut rather an IE Addon but a great one at that!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
